Magda Stefanescu

Bucharest, Romania Cell phone / WhatsApp: +40 731 903 926 Email: magstefanescu@yahoo.com Skype ID: Bundy Bu

Experience Summary:

Over 15 years' experience in finance and administration positions for large international corporations. Coordinating, organizing full activities, and efficiently solving the problems of offices in Afghanistan, Iraq, Azerbaijan and Romania. Successfully led a multinational accounting staff. Recognized as a superior performer through rapid promotions and increased responsibilities. Demonstrated the ability to successfully manage budgets, processes and people in high-stress situations. Excellent leadership and communications skills with persons at all levels that contribute to a cohesive team environment.

Professional Experience:

Senior Financial/Accounting Analyst

Swift Consulting Group Ltd.

Baku, Azerbaijan

January 2016 - August 2016

- Responsible for performing the day-to-day general ledger accounting, financial reporting and analysis for assigned functional areas
- Research and resolve Business Unit(s) inquiries for assigned functional areas
- Routine communication with supervisors relating to financial close, issues and deliverables
- Responsible for month-end, quarter-end and year-end close for assigned functional areas
- Research and prepare variance analysis and explanations
- Complete and submit required report deliverables
- Responsible for the preparation and analysis of the periodic management reporting of financial results for assigned functional areas
- Prepare all financial reporting requirements package
- Perform balance sheet account reconciliations, account analysis, accrual calculations, and other related accounting documents/schedules
- Prepare journal entries related to assigned functional responsibilities
- Prepare foreign currency transaction analysis and its impact on financial results
- Calculate withholding tax entries as applicable
- Responsible for performing special projects to improve process efficiency and performance
- Cross train as back-up for other staff in the case of emergencies
- Review and research accounting transactions for functional areas
- Participate in creation of chart of account structure and other associated financial structuring as required
- Perform budget forecasting and planning as required by the CFO

AP/AR Manager

Shield Security Services

Kabul, Afghanistan

June 2014 -March 2015

- Invoicing of customers for monthly services
- Cash payments acc. invoices, PO, cash advances
- Withdrawal of money from a bank account
- Investigating circumstances of non-payment and posting in QB received payments
- Daily receipts, posting transfers and cash expenses in to QB system
- Prepare the payroll for Shield employees (US, EU, Nepalese and locals)
- Wire the salaries and pay by cash salaries for locals and cash advances for EU and locals
- Monthly payment for tickets, mobiles, medical services, renting of vehicles, Stratex charges

- Monthly reports
- Reconciliations and balances Shield-Cochise (every quarter)

Senior Office Administrator

DynCorp International FZ

Kabul, Afghanistan

May 2010- September 2013

- Develop and maintain the office budget and all required reports including bank and petty cash accounts
- Review and authorize billing invoices and ensure payment is received in a timely manner.
- Prepare and review expense reports and prepare the cash flows
- Ensure compliance with company policies, procedures, record keeping and other practices
- Write and maintain reports to update management on relevant information
- Insurance compliance with all applicable regulations, policies and local Afghanistan laws
- Code and track invoices to ensure accuracy and timely payment
- Maintain and track costs and performance against office budget
- Preparation of financial reports including BVA reports; audit accounts payable and payroll for accuracy
- Manage the bank reconciliation, checking accounts and petty cash fund
- Communicate with vendors, suppliers and internal departments to investigate and resolve problems associated with processing of invoices
- Administrate procurement, subcontract, travel and property control functions
- Prepare all the tax withholding for employees, vendors and leases; prepare the reports and the MOF tax forms; make payments to the banks
- Prepare and coordinate all HR actions for the office (FSAs, updating and maintaining personal files
 for all personnel), analyze and organize office operations and procedures such as preparation of time
 sheets, personnel, information management, filing systems, requisition of supplies and other clerical
 services

Accountant & Office Administrator

Kirkuk Cement Company Ltd. Kirkuk & Erbil Iraq (Headquarter in Germany) October 2008-March 2009

- Managed eight persons in the Administrative Department that was responsible for the performance of all office administrative work in Kirkuk. Also responsible for the coordinated, efficient flow of documents between departments located in Germany and Iraq
- Responsible for coordinating and preparing all aspects of accountancy for the German and Iraq
 offices.
- Processed Employee Change Notification (ECN) or other related Human Resources data within the Human Resources Information System (HRIS) database.
- Collected and analyzed relevant statistical data and prepared reports for senior management.
- Responsible for all recruiting activities of the company. Insured that all HR policies supported the corporate business strategies and were in compliance with legal and corporate policies. Developed and implemented effective recruiting strategies (web, referral, agencies) which resulted in attracting talented new employees into the organization.
- Provided guidance to employees regarding company policies and procedures for all Human Resources functions
- Checked pending files for discrepancies and ensured timely follow-up to resolve problems
- Responsible for in-processing of new and transferred employees in accordance with company Standard Operating Procedures (SOP). Ensured appropriate approved documents were received and were in compliance with company regulations and local employment laws.

Account Supervisor

PAE (US Embassy subcontractor)

Baghdad, Iraq

September 2007-September 2008

- Managed the Finance Department
- Responsible for a monthly cash budget of approximately \$200,000.00
- Responsible for all accounting activities to include: petty cash, payroll, journal transactions, general
 ledger, expenses, expenditures, accounts payable/receivable, purchase orders, salaries/wages, time
 sheets, incidentals, receipts, payments, advances, accounts and bank reconciliations.
- Prepared monthly reports regarding expenses and revenues plus various other management reports
- Prepared and disbursed monthly salary payments. Maintained required payment records in accordance with standard accounting principles.

Promoted from Accountant to Accountant Supervisor based on outstanding performance, job knowledge and leadership skills.

Chief Accountant

UTI GROUP Bucharest, Romania

September 2006-September 2007

(A system integrator providing complete solutions for security systems, information technology and communications, and civil engineering)

- Chief Accountant responsible for managing the Commercial Department and all associated accounting activities for the company.
- Supervised an office staff of five accounting administrators.
- Managed an annual budget of approximately 2000 euro per department
- Prepared various accounting/budget reports as required.
- Prepared the budgets for five departments
- Promoted from Economist to Chief Accountant based on outstanding performance, initiative, technical knowledge and superb communications skills.

Economist

EuroStar Cont. SA

Bucharest, Romania

September 2003-September 2006

- Provided accounting expertise for up to seven companies; from primary accountancy to closing reports and balance sheets in accordance with the laws
- Provided oversight for declarations, bank transfers, bank accounts, balance sheets, monthly and annual closings
- Supported the audit with information requested for the seven companies' financial situation
- Facilitated positive relations between the company and the bank
- Kept records for all the financial, accounting and HR for the companies

Central Military Hospital

Bucharest, Romania

November 1997-September 2003

Accountant

- Provided primary accountancy, receipts and bookkeeping for Governmental Company
- Keeping the files up-date for the Financial Department
- Provided procurement (quotes, PR, PO, invoices) in accordance with the laws

Education:

MBA, Rivier University, NH, USA

September 2017 – December 2017

Bachelor's Degree, Academy of Economic Studies of Bucharest, Romania

September 1998–September 2003

The Faculty of Management, Specialization in Corporate Management

The Economic High School No. 5 Costin C. Kiritescu

Specialization Accountant - Statistician

September 1992- June 1996

Collaboration:

- Collaboration V. Taurus as Assistant Manager and Cashier October 2003 April 2004
- Collaboration within the accounting department as Economist at EIPICO December 2004 August 2005
- Collaboration within public relations department to promote products of ROMSAR COSMETICS and S.C.

VINARTE **2004**, **2005**

Knowledge, Skills and Abilities Skills:

Computer skills:

• Software /Applications: Microsoft Office, MS WORD (excellent), MS EXCEL (excellent), MS ACCESS (very good), ZEUS (good), MS OUTLOOK(excellent), MS POWER POINT (excellent), NORTON COMMANDER (good), AXEL (beginner); QuickBooks, MICROSOFT DYNAMICS (SOLOMON), RSI, ELO, Professional,

QUICKEN, Outlook Express, Internet Explorer (excellent)

- Computer languages: HTML5, CSS3, jQuery, PHP, elements Bootstrap
- Management: Innovative, self-starter who thrives on challenges in stressful work environments. Maintains an unselfish company first attitude. Challenges subordinate to achieve high standards.
- Initiative and a can-do attitude
- Leadership: Leads by example. Sets a positive, team oriented focus. Enthusiastic winning attitude.
- **Communications: Excellent** written and communications skills with persons at all levels. Dynamic personality who motivates others to succeed and do what is necessary to get the job done.
- **Driving license:** B category issued in 18.05.2001. (Side note: I also drove in Iraq)

Very good health. International Health Certificate— issued in 2009 (Side note: I travelled in Europe, Africa, USA, Alaska, Caribbean Islands, Mauritius and New Zealand)

Foreign Languages:

- English Fluent Advanced courses at British Council Bucharest and FIDES School Bucharest.
 Ability to communicate, write and read fluently in the English language IELTS Academic certificates overall band 6, 5
- French Intermediate High School classes and final exam
- Italian–Basic
- Spanish Basic and medium conversational

Certificates

- Subcontract Management and Administration Course within DynCorp International Dubai, 16 to 27 May 2010
- Web design, Digital Skills SRL March-April 2017
- The European Certificates for Communication & Competence

 —Certificate in Italian language issued the School Studio Italia, Rome, and April 2007
- English language IELTS Academic 6,5 overall Feb, 2017
- English courses FIDES School Bucharest, June 2007
- English British Council Bucharest IELTS courses certificates, November 2016
- Accountancy field—Certificate for Accounting and Statistician profession, August 1996
- Course IT-Military Central Hospital, IT Department, April 1998

====References upon request===